Alexey Taktarov, Full-Stack Dev

ROSTOV-ON-DON, RUSSIA · +7 (918) 579-28-43

PROFILE

Experienced and reliable full-stack web developer with a good sense of design and full of creative ideas.

My main area of interest *includes interactive* single-page web applications built on top of React/Redux, Ember.js and Vue.js. I write well-documented and tested server-side code using Node.js or Ruby on Rails. Found myself really passionate about UX/UI: I like building systems which will be understandable, clean and have design integrity from bottom-up. I also enjoy working on data visualizations and 2D/3D graphical experiments.

In the meantime I'm a member of a non-profit community Code Hipsters: we organise local IT-meetups, write frontend-digest in social media and do some open-source. Things I've played around recently: **Go, CycleJS, Rx, FRP.**

- GitHub: https://github.com/molefrog
- CodePen: http://codepen.io/molefrog

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full-Stack Engineer, resume.io

Jul. 2016, Remote

Together with a friend of mine and colleague Tikhon (we work together under the brand**These Guys**) we built a working web-based resume generator for the client from Netherlands. We got first working prototype and our first paying customer in less than a week; the current client base of *resume.io* is around 10k users now.

The service runs on top of **Ruby on Rails**, has **Sidekiq** background jobs services, *Slack* integration, built-in analytics, email campaign editor and **Stripe** support while the core UI is working on **React/Redux/Redux Saga**. The client is able to launch the product on new markets in just a click: resume.io is i18n-friendly and is customisable for each country in the admin area. I've built the entire architecture of a service and was responsible for the development on both server and client side: from SEO/PageSpeed tweaks and markup to DevOps-related work.

Fun fact: the resume you're reading now is generated on resume.io.

Front-End Developer, Evil Martians Jun. 2016 – Aug. 2016, Remote work

Was working remotely with Evil Martians team *evilmartians.com* during the summer of 2016 developing client-side part of one of the **YC'2015** startups. The project was built on top of Ruby on Rails backend with the React/Redux for UI. The stylesheets were organised with BEM methodology and written in SCSS.

Developer/Team Lead, Smartomato Feb. 2014 – May. 2016, Rostov-on-Don

I've built the architecture and have implemented 3 client-side single-page apps all written using

DETAILS

Rostov-on-Don, Russia +7 (918) 579-28-43 molefrog@gmail.com

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

01/15/1991

NATIONALITY

Russian

DRIVING LICENSE

B/Russian

SKILLS

React/Redux

Ruby on Rails

Ember.js

Node.js

D3/Canvas/Physics

C/C++

HOBBIES

Conference Talks, Comic Books, Flying Kites, Documetaries, Cats

LANGUAGES

English

Russian

Ember.js framework and Ember.Data; one of the apps was built on top of PhoneGap/Cordova platform. Besides that I did experiments with React and React.Native and was responsible for collecting UI components in a unified Ember UI kit. I also made a design of some of the components.

I did Ruby on Rails and API development and wrote several 3rd party integrations: POS-terminals, delivery websites etc.

Front-End Developer, Grapheme Sep. 2013 – Feb. 2014, Rostov-on-Don

Built several web-experiments and advert projects using Node.js, Socket.io, Web Audio API and Canvas APIs. Was using Lavarel framework for back-end code. Some of the tools I've built during my work at Grapheme are open-sourced.

EDUCATION

Southern Federal University, Masters in Applied Math and Computer Science

Sep. 2008 - Jun. 2014, Rostov-on-Don

Hogskolan i Halmstad, Exchange programme

Jan. 2013 - Jun. 2013, Halmstad, Sweden

As a part of Erasmus programme I've been studying Electrical Engineering in Halmstad University *(hh.se)* in Sweden. During the semester I was attending 4 courses in total, all focused around embedded, real-time and cyber-physical systems.

With the help of my parter Jonas I've built a model of a ping-pong robot.

COURSES

Metaprogramming in Ruby, by Dave Thomas

Mar. 2016

Cyber-Physical Systems, Hogskolan i Halmstad

Feb. 2013

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Developer/Co-owner, Ficus.io

Oct. 2015 - Present, Rostov-on-Don

Ideologist/Community and Meetup Organizer, Code Hipsters

Feb. 2014 – Present, Rostov-on-Don/Moscow

REFERENCES

Menno Olsthoorn, Resume.io

skype: menno89 – info@imkey.nl

Eugene Pshenichniy, Code Hipsters/Ficus.io

+7 (906) 439-71-16 – pshenichniy.eugene@gmail.com

Alexander Khatlamadziev, Hatlam/Smartomato

+7 (918) 558-73-99 - hatlam@hatlam.com

Vitaly Bragilevsky, Southern Federal University

+7 (960) 461-51-06 – bravit@rsu.ru